9/26/2019 index.htm

Ayesha Raza

Download PDF Sykesville, MD

(410) 865-9939 araza1@umd.edu github.com/razaayesha336

Technical Skills

Objective: Wireshark

analysis

An honor student pursuing a degree in Information Science specializing in Data Science and CyberSecurity with an ultimate goal of becoming an Data Scientist. Willing to take steps to go down the path and apply my experience assisting a company to maintain data integrity.

Network analysis

Education:

Penetration

Bachelor of Science in Information Science: Data Science & December Cybersecurity Specialization.

2020

MySql

WorkbenchUniversity of Maryland, College Park, MD

Associate of Arts in Network Security.

GPA 4.0 | December 2016

R Studio

Howard Community College, Coulmbia, MD

Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society.

2015 - Present

Languages

MD State Senatorial Scholarship FT.

2016-Present

HTML Sigma Alpha Pi. 2016-Present

Experience:

R

Service Desk Technician

August 2018 - Present

MySql

University of Maryland, College Park, MD

C++

- Interface with multiple level of users, management, VIPs, and technical staff concerning first level needs.
- Assist customers seeking technical assistance over the phone or live chat.
- Identifies and escalates situations requiring urgent attention.
- Use a ticketing system to track and route problems and requests and document solutions.
- Use a ticketing system to track and route problems and requests and document solutions.
- Determines whether problems are caused by hardware or software, and resolves calls immediately with the customer.
- Perform remote troubleshooting through diagnostic techniques and pertinent questions.
- Works with the service desk team to research and document problem resolutions.

Assistant Directory & Camp Counselor for Google December 2016 – July igniteCS 2017

Howard Community College, Columbia, MD

- Taught middle school girls about software and coding, robotics, Raspberry Pi Technology, and 3D printing.
- They learned coding and built meme and sites with coding.

9/26/2019 index.htm

■ Taught them different computer languages: such as Java, HTML, CSS etc.

Cyber-Security Intern

January 2017 - February 2017

Howard Community College, Columbia, MD

- Created a Network template for a theoretical small business to use as a reference in future to protect their network against broader range of malicious threats.
- Drafted Acceptable Use Policy (AUP).
- Researched and created a report related to security clearance and cleaning up social profiles for individuals looking for a job in the Government sector.

Math Tutor

August 2015 - May 2017

Howard Community College, Columbia, MD

- · Assisted students individually and in small groups in targeted areas.
- Provided supplemental assignments to ascertain level of understanding.

Relevant Coursework:

- Dynamic Web Applications.
- Systematic Program Design I & II.
- Decision-Making for Information Science.
- Statistics for Information Science.
- Database Design and Modeling.
- Intrusion Detection Systems.
- Network Security Systems.
- Ethical Hacking and Cyber Defense.

